Guide to the Lydik S. Jacobsen Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Lydik S. Jacobsen papers
1948-1958
SC0235
Jacobsen, Lydik S.
0.5 Linear feet
Miscellaneous correspondence and other papers relating to Professor Jacobsen's research interests in seismology and structural dynamics.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, School of Engineering, 1980.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor Jacobsen began his teaching career at Stanford in 1924. He headed the Mechanical Engineering Department, 1940-1943, and directed the Earthquake Research Laboratory, 1926-1943 and 1946-1962; received his a.b. in mechanical engineering from Stanford in 1921 and his Ph.D. in Physics here in 1927. Jacobsen died in 1976.
Description of the Collection
Miscellaneous correspondence and other papers relating to Professor Jacobsen's research interests in seismology and structural dynamics.
Access Terms
Jacobsen, Lydik S.; Jacobsen, Lydik S.; Stanford University. Department of Mechanical Engineering. Faculty.; Stanford University. Department of Mechanical Engineering. -- General subdivision--Faculty.;; Stanford University. Earthquake Research Laboratory.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Structure dynamic proposals (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Structure dynamic progress report (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Structure dynamic equipment (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Structure dynamic, letters, distribution list (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dr. Rees (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Seismology (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Vibration research, ONR (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - ERI - Earthquake engineering research (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - ERI 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - ERI 1949 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - ERI 1950 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - ERI 1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - ERI 1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous 1953-1958: letter and alumni questionnaire from John Van Amringe, 1954; letter-report on Stanford-in-Germany, 1958; memo re alumni questionnaire 1953 (Box 1, Folder 15)